Chick-fil-A makes more than these three businesses combined.
So here are the six things they do
that you can apply to your business.
Number one is focus.
They focused on selling chicken sandwiches
for the past 59 years in making the chicken sandwich
better and better and better.
Number two, they built slowly.
Chick-fil-A grew slowly, didn't take on debt as family owned.
It's competitor in the early days Boston market
who as fast as they could took on debt
when public announced out of business.
Number three, values.
Chick-fil-A could increase their sales by 13%,
or $650 million per year by simply being open on Sunday.
But they don't let money compromise their values
which makes them more money in the long term.
Number four, hospitality.
They hired people from Ritz Carlton
to help them create exquisite experiences at Chick-fil-A.
Number five, compounding.
They buy the land and the building
for each door they build
so over time the real estate value continues
to go up and compound.
Number six, they don't change their menu.
And this is huge.
They just get better and better at what they sell.
So instead of being mediocre at many things,
they're exceptional at a few.
Their menu is a quarter of the size
of many other big faster chains
and all the stuff down there is arguably, in my opinion, better.
Tactics like these help me build my portfolio of companies
that generate over $250 million annually.
You can follow for more business breakdowns.